geekyfaust.info 2012-12-17

# Privacy Policy | GeekyFaust | Philippines, Gadget Reviews, Technology News

**Introduction and Terms**

geekyfaust.info is committed to protecting your personal information when you are using our service. We want this to be a safe and enjoyable environment for our audience. This Privacy Policy relates to our use of any personal information you provide to us through the various user interfaces available on geekyfaust.info.

In order to provide you with the full range of services, we are sometimes required to collect information about you.

As set out above, geekyfaust.info is committed to safeguarding your personal information. Whenever you provide such information, we are legally obliged to use your information in line with all pertinent and applicable laws concerning the protection of personal information.

The website contains hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third-party websites have their own privacy policies, and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit or are collected by cookies while visiting these other websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third-party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

**What information will be collected about me?**

When you sign up to participate in, or receive a service from, the geekyfaust.info website, such as newsletters, competitions, live chats, message boards, etc., we may ask for personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number or date of birth. Different web pages may ask for different personal information.

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable geekyfaust.info and its service providers to provide you with the services you select.

Please note that sometimes on particular web pages we will require you to provide additional personal information, and sometimes sensitive personal information (e.g., if you use our contact form). When we do this we will specify further on these web pages why we are collecting your information and how we will use it.

geekyfaust.info also uses cookies and collects IP addresses (an IP address is a number that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet). We use analysis software to look at IP addresses and cookies for the purpose of enhancing your user experience. This information is not used to develop a personal profile of you and the log files are regularly purged.

**How will geekyfaust.info use the information collected about me?**

geekyfaust.info will use your personal information for a number of purposes, including the following:

  * for service administration purposes, which means that we may contact you for reasons related to the service you have signed up for, as set out below (e.g., to provide you with password reminders or to notify you that a particular service has been suspended for maintenance);
  * to contact you about a submission you have made to the website, including any content you provide;
  * to personalize the way content is presented to you;
  * IP addresses are used to identify the location of users, the number of visits from different countries and also to block disruptive use; and
  * to analyze and improve the services offered on geekyfaust.info, e.g., to provide you with the most user-friendly navigation experience.

Where geekyfaust.info proposes using your personal information for any other use, we will ensure that we notify you first. You will also be given the opportunity to withhold or withdraw your consent for your use other than as listed above.

**When will geekyfaust.info contact me?**

geekyfaust.info may contact you:

  * in relation to the functioning of any service you have signed up for in order to ensure that geekyfaust.info can deliver the services to you;
  * where you have opted to receive further correspondence;
  * in relation to any contribution you have made to the website, e.g., on post comments;
  * to invite you to participate in surveys about our services (participation is always voluntary); and
  * for marketing purposes where you have specifically agreed to this.

**Will I be contacted for promotional purposes?**

geekyfaust.info won’t contact you for promotional purposes, or promote new services to you unless you specifically agree to be contacted for these purposes.

**Will geekyfaust.info share my personal information with anyone else?**

We will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (e.g., to government bodies and law enforcement agencies, upon receipt of a subpoena), or as described below. Generally, we will only use your information within the website. However, sometimes geekyfaust.info uses third parties to process your information (such as Google Analytics). geekyfaust.info will require these third parties to comply strictly with its instructions and we will require that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes.

**Offensive or inappropriate content on geekyfaust.info**

If you post or send offensive, spam, inappropriate or objectionable content anywhere on or to geekyfaust.info, or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on the website, geekyfaust.info may use your personal information to stop such behaviour.

Where geekyfaust.info reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of any of the laws of the Republic of the Philippines (e.g., because content you have posted may be defamatory or libelous), geekyfaust.info may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as your employer, Internet provider or law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour.

**What if I am a user aged 16 or under?**

If you are aged 17 or under, please get your parent/guardian’s permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to the geekyfaust.info website. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.

**How long will geekyfaust.info keep my personal information?**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant service, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with geekyfaust.info. In the case that you wish to cancel your registration as an geekyfaust.info member, it stays on the system for a period of one year for administration purposes before being deleted automatically.

Where you contribute to geekyfaust.info, we will generally only keep your content for as long as is reasonably required for the purpose(s) for which it was submitted.

geekyfaust.info also has an obligation to record snapshots of history which may include some User Generated Content, i.e., content provided by users. Therefore, some content submitted to or shared with geekyfaust.info may be retained for prolonged periods of time or potentially indefinitely in our archives, which is true of news contributions, which are published. There may also be rare instances where we will share your contribution with third parties in the interests of maintaining historical archives. Where possible, we will endeavor to inform you upfront or let you know at a later date where we are likely to keep content indefinitely or pass it on to an approved historical archive.

**Cookies Policy** — Information geekyfaust.info collects from you

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your computer (referred to here as a “device”) browser from a website’s computer and is stored on your device’s hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Many sites do this whenever a user visits their website in order to track online traffic flows.

Cookies record information about your online preferences and allow us to tailor the websites to your interests. Users have the opportunity to set their devices to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these means that certain personalized services cannot then be provided to that user and accordingly you may not be able to take full advantage of all of the geekyfaust.info features. Each browser is different, so check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

During the course of any visit to geekyfaust.info, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your device. Many websites do this, because cookies enable website publishers to do useful things like find out whether the device (and probably its user) has visited the website before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.

**How does geekyfaust.info use cookies?**

Information supplied by cookies can help us to analyze the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user collaborative experience.
